Blessing I. Lova

SUMMARY/OBJECTIVE

| lovab_101@outlook.com | 352a Athelney Rd Ruwa|

I am a skilled and knowledgeable Technician who has excellent installation, troubleshooting, and advanced knowledge of computer information technology. I possess excellent oral and written communication skills. I am a born ICT enthusiast, which gives me a direct, quick hint in problem-solving as to where a possible solution is needed. I have one and a half years of experience in the industry. I seek to improve and develop more relevant skills to showcase more of my undiscovered talents.

WORK EXPERIENCE

+263774969259

Ruwa Local Board, Ruwa — ICT Intern AUGUST 2021-MAY 2022

- Windows Server Administration (Disk Management and Monitoring of shared services)
- Progress Database Administration
- Network Administration, troubleshooting and problem solving
- Problem-solving of all ICT related issues that arose
- Sending of Bulk SMSs to clients
- Diagnosis and repairing of Desktop PCs and laptops
- Graphical designing of council graphical content
- Sophos Firewall administration (authentication and approval/disapproval of access to the internet)
- was a representative on the ICT Help Desk
- Promun System Support (Unlocking locked users and troubleshooting & solving any causes of client and server system failure scenarios)

Info Relay Systems, Msasa — IT Technician AUGUST 2023 - PRESENT

- LTE installations and fault attendance for Liquid Intelligent Technologies
- WIFI Offloads Access Point Installation, configuration and fault attendance for Liquid Intelligent Technologies
- Client and customer support for Metro Peech & Browne wholesalers

EDUCATION

Midlands State University

Academic Excellence in Information Systems with a 2.1 Upper Second Class (Overall Score)

Bcomm in Information Systems 2019 - 2022 Gweru, Midlands.

Trust Academy in collaboration with Midlands State University

Academic Excellence in Management
Information Systems with a Credit (Overall
Score)

Diploma in Management Information Systems

2017 - 2018

Harare.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ✓ Installation & Troubleshooting
- ✓ Networking
- ✓ Credible knowledge of Office & 365 packages
- ✓ Computer Diagnosis, Repair &
 Maintenance

- Client and customer support for Metro Wholesalers and Metro Hypermarket
- Checkpoint Endpoint Antivirus monitoring on Servers and client machines
- Fincon Accounting Software client support (installation, linking software to server, creating users and updating user roles)
- Fincon Accounting Technical Support (Creation and edition of templates for fiscalisation)
- Sophos firewall Administration (Internet Usage monitoring, authentication and approval/disapproval of access on the internet)
- Remote client support though Anydesk and Team Viewer
- Performing remote troubleshooting through diagnostic techniques and pertinent questions
- Assigning roles and creating local accounts on servers and clients
- Sage Pastel Accounting Technical Support (Installation, maintenance and troubleshoot)
- Printer Setup, configurations, diagnosis and troubleshooting
- Use of Firewall Administration tools and Network Management Consoles (Unifi Controller, Sophos Firewall Report Compiler and Cisco network monitoring utilities)
- Microwave Link Radio configurations
- Determining the best solution based on the issue and details provided by clients
- Server Staging
- Computer System Diagnosis and troubleshooting
- Windows installation, Recovery, repair and upgrades
- Cleaning and Servicing of Computers
- Network Administration, troubleshooting and problem solving
- Office 365 Administration
- Performing Network Configurations
- Problem-solving of all ICT related issues that arise
- Consistent Internet Speed Monitoring to ensure minimised downtime of critical services running by taking possible measures that sustain availability

LANGUAGES

- ✓ English
- ✓ Shona

SOFT SKILLS

- ✓ Effective communicator
- ✓ Team oriented
- ✓ Problem-solving

REFERENCES

Mr Pasura

Assistant Systems Administrator

Ruwa Local Board

+263 773 122 626

joepasura@gmail.com

Mr Mupfunde

Managing Director

Info Relay Systems

+263 772 484 693

cliff@irs.co.zw

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENCES ISC2 CYBERSECURITY ENTRY-LEVEL CERTIFICATION

BRIEF SUMMARY OF ATTRIBUTES:

- ✓ Security Principles
- ✓ Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response
 Concepts
- ✓ Access Controls Concepts
- ✓ Network Security
- ✓ Security Operations